<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-jazz/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045217/1921-01-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jazz+Saxophone&r=0.021,0.849,0.508,0.256,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Saxophone Wail, Jazz
Make Indians Wild
Again, Says Pastor
Philadelphia, Jan. 21.—Modern
jazz music and dancing are making
the Indians wild again. The roll of
the snare drum and the wail of the
saxophone, combined with the "tod
dle" and the "shimmy" stir atavistic
memories of the tom-tom and the
shriek of the victim at the stake.
So asserted Dr. Henry Beets of
Grand Rapids, Mich., secretary of
missions of the Christian Reformed
church, in an address Friday before
the session of the Friends of the
Indian.
A resolution he introduced seek
ing to forbid Indian youths and girls
from dancing the modern steps, was
adopted and will be sent to the In
dian bureau of the department of
the interior at Washington.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093354/1921-02-01/ed-1/?sp=10&q=jazz&r=0.102,0.255,0.647,0.327,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Just what is jazz? One has a vague idea of a dis
orderly number of sounds played entirely for dancing.
But jazz has a far deep.r significance. It is an attempt
to reproduce the marvelous syncopation of the African
Jungle. It is the result of the savage musican's won
derful gift of progressive retarding and acceleration
which is guided by his sense of ewing. He who would
play ja^z nnut have rhythmic aggressiveness. As one
iran put it, ja: z music is the rtelirum tr mens of suyco
pL.i'on. It n strict rhythm without melody.
The words ja;, jazz, jazz, J&3Z, and jascz are of
Afrcan origin but come direct form the Creole patois
and idiom meaning "speed things up." For in th> old
plantation days when the slaves were having one of their
rare holidays an fun would languish, some West Coast
African would say, "jazz hdT up," and then things would
go fast and furious. Today "jazz her up," is still a
slang expression with the same meaning.
There are two types of jazz: One originating in
China, which is called Siames 3 music, and the other
originating in Africa having only a general name of
jazz applied to it. Since the Siamese music or Oriental
jazz, as it is often called, stay:d strictly in China and
underwent no futher development it is not important.
But the jazz that originated in Africa, or the Occidental
jazz is known the world ov-r and because of its impor
tance w> will trace its growth only.
Occidental jazz first came to life on the West Coast
of Africa. There big sturdy warriers danced to tli? music
of throbbing Tom —Toms while the entire jungle was
the accompanying orchestra.
Then it spread, reaching Cuba thru deported slaves.
It found a rich soil there for its growth, since the
jungles of Africa were not so different from the swamps
of Cuba. All of that "Hula Hula stuff," goes straight
back to Africa for its origin. Then jazz was transplanted
into America, entering from the south and creeping
up until it covered all of America. About that time the
war broke out and when our boys went to Europe and
and especially to France they took their beloved jazz
with them. So Paris was initiated into a new world of
music over which they promptly went wild.
But jazz has found her strongest support in the
United States. When jazz arived in America via New
Crleans it almost died leaving only a little spark fostered
by the slaves and New Orleans underworld. For years
jazz has ruled the New Orleans underworld resorts,
thei>- natrons dancing to jazz for gladsome generations
Ragtime and the new dances came from there. Then
slowly, little by little, jazz crept up the Missippi from
resort to resort until it landed in Chicago at Freiburg's
whither it had been proceded by stanzas of "Must I
Hesitate"? "The Blues", 'Frankie and Johnnie," and
other classics of the levee underworld that seems to
please the savage part of us. From there it spread
like wild fire all over the United States, hitting the
Middle West the hardest and the extreme East the
lightest. Jazz has reigned supreme for some years and
CAYTON'S MONTH! V
most likely, will reign for many more for it has invaded
our dance halls, theaters, and concert halls. Even our
churchs have not escaped without their share of tem
petious music. It has even snatched our very song»,
classical and popular, and taken them for its own use
ragging them to death.
One use to think of a band as a group of respectable
looking beings usally with a splendid musical ability.
But when one gazes upon a jazz band he sees a bunch of
s .emingly demented men, contorting themselves and
their instruments far better than a St Vitis dancer.
For the modern jazz band is in reality a young army
artillery. The howitzers of the band ara stationed in
the trap drum, snare drum, cymbals, triangle, wooden
blocks, xylophone, cow bells, rattles and whistles for
the production of various weried noises. The trome
bones represent the field guns, the clarinets, oboes,
saxophones, auto homes and cornets furnish thol rapid
lire batteries. The range being point blank one can
easily s^e why the effect of the drum fire is so complete.
Some say that jazz is sensual. If so why has it
lived in America so long? For this reason: Jazz is of
tho ravage and therefore clemntal in its appeal. It is
bouterous, rough, but the very soul of kindly good
humor and care free merriment. It is the music siren
of the dance for while one is swept thru a neck breaking,
whirl-wind measura his own cares and responsibilities
are brushed aside. In America especially because we,
;00, are of a strenous nature, we nejd and must find
some sort of energetic exercise as a conteractant. The
old fashioned, dreamy waltez and graceful, measured
minuets are things of the past. The tired business man,
the worn out mother, the discouraged poet, as well as
the impatient youths, seek and find relief in jazz. Then
ddi not th dough boys find a wonderful solace in their
beloved jazz? For while under its throes they forgot
the bloody battle field, the stench of decaying bodies;
they even forgot there was such a thing as war. Then
jazz is d mocratic. It is simple enough for any one to
understand and enough of a vampire to coax every one
into a world of oblivion. Can we not then say that jazz
has existed for a purpose and has truly fulfilled that
purpos;.?
But on the other hand one must be careful that the
alluring god of jazz, Mumbo Jumbo, does not lead us so
far from the true god of music, Pan, that we fail to
appr ciate the real classic. Might not one thus uncon
sciouly sell his birth-right for a mess of pottage?
Because jazz is elemental bringing the savage to the
curface, it is dang rous. We cannot afford in our
present stage of civilization to accept the standard of
the savage even if it is only thru the giddy measure of
a dance. True jazz belongs to the "forest primeval"
and is mor: real and refined there than in a hall filled
with dancer.3. The very fact that the growth of jazz
las been thru the under world resorts of America is a
E rong po'nt in i's disfavor. In embrasing what we
now c..11 a necessary evil is there not a chance of jazz
becoming the key to open our souls to the passions our
fore fathers nave spent generations in trying to over
come</text>
      </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-08-15/ed-1/?sp=55&q=danc+Dance+dancing+jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>JAZZ," that root of much
evil in music, a menace to
established rythmical law
and order and beauty and
grace, is dying its slow but natural
death
Syncopation which tends ^toward
"shimmying," wriggling and hop?
ping about dance floors as in the
days cf prehistoric barbarism is dis?
appearing and, according to those
authorities who make it their busi?
ness to study dancing, the demise of
"jazz" occasions more general joy
than sorrow. Puritanical grand?
mothers and perhaps less prudish
fathers and mothers who attend and
chaperon social dances of the young
need not much longer blush when
their eyes sweep the ballroom. The
youth of the nation may, after all,
grow up amidst less sensuous music
and dancing positions which em?
barrass their elders. A reaction
against this sort of thing is in full
swing in the United States and, like
a burned out plague, "jazz" music
and "jazz" dancing are leaving us.
While "jazz"' still retains its ad?
mirers and supporters, its own
ridiculousness has done more toward
it? eliminatii n than any other agen?
cy, believes Fenton T. Bott, presi?
dent of the American National As?
sociation, Masters of Dancing, who
is now in New York to attend the
thirty- annual convention of
that association, beginning August
25, at the Hotel Astor.
For Clean Dancing
The association, with it? more
than five hundred active members in
every city cf any r-ize in the UYiited
States and Canada, has been one of
the agencies working quietly since
the advent of "jazz" to keep danc?
ing clean and moral. In coopera?
tion with many civic and welfare so?
cieties throughout the country, much
has been done to eliminate the sala
ciou: and immoral features which
this form of syncopation brought
he dance floor.
"We do not recognize the terrr
'jazz,' which is purely a coined
word," Mr. Bot; told The Tribune
"We ever, recognize synco
d.we have nothing agai?.si
of syncopated music.
It can be playi i so brilliantly if
played right, and then again it can
ther form so sensu?
ous and evil that it harks clear back
to the wild and irresponsible barba?
rism of the dark ages. We have
tried and preach modera?
tion. Civilization has begun to re?
volt against the wrong kind of syn?
copation, tins so-called 'jazz,' whicr
during tne more unrestrained perioc
of the war swept the country witl
a crop of immodesty in both son?
and dance in its wake. It first ap
peared on the stage, and eventually
it audaciously entered the publi;
dance hail and private ballroon
alike.
"There is a decided upward tren?
in music now, as compared with i
year ago," continued the dance mas
ter president. "New York, a leade
in entertainment whose example i
followed everywhere, is setting
cleaner pace. Compare New York'
roof gardens of some of the leadin?
hotels, compare the theaters, th
moving picture palaces and even th
dance halls now with a year age
Twelve months ago the 'jazz' crnz
was everywhere. It was reflecte^
from the stage, the dance floor anc
in a wave of ribald, suggestive song
Written and distributed to every cot
ner of the land. It invaded th
home in the form of magazine il
lustrations, on lithographed cover
of sheet music, in graphophone an
pianola records.
Displaced hy Good Musie
"To-day we find 'jazz' dying
natural death. This form of syncc
Pation is giving way in motion pi<
tore houses to pipe organs and grea
orchestras playing real and beaut
f'Jl music, it is to be heard less i
a11 the theaters. The r?of garde
dancing inclosures are reflecting let
and less the ridiculous movements c
oncers inspired by slow, barbaror
?Ksic Public dance halls are fa
?leaner, if we are to believe the at
%rities. And all of this is n(
toly true of New York but of th
country at large."
The president of the America
National Association, Masters
Dancing, ?3 a citizen of Daytoi
Ohio, where he conducts a dancin
Waden-y attended by juvenile men
oers of some of Dayton'a first fam
including "Young Jimmy" Co:
a?ed fourteen, son of the Democrat
nominee for President.
"It is such folks as these that ov
association seeks to protect in i
campaign for cleaner dancing ar
ottner music," he said. "We do n
concern ourselves with the ty]
JJwch demanda vulgarity and lice
Jiousness. They are not of our pro
But, as an organization, v
*?st a stand against that so
J- thing if we aro to hold up 01
'?ttds/*
There has been virtually no op?
position to the anti-jazz campaign
waged by his organization except
from a few unscrupulous dance hall
proprietors, said the president.
"Dancing is an essential," he
added. "What would tens of thou?
sands of people do nightly in New
York if they were not permitted to
go somewhere, meet socially, and
dance? If the places where these
people meet are decent there can be
no finer, more healthful or enjoy?
able recreation anywhere."
"What do you consider good or
bad positions in dancing?" he was
asked.
"It is difficult to illustrate posi?
tions," he answered. "Anyone can
see with a glance over the dance
floor wdiether positions are good or
bad. When you take hold of a girl
to dance, common sense and decency
should prompt your position. If your
attitude toward her is proper, you
will not crush your body against
hers nor place your cheek against
hers.
A Form of Exercise
"Clean dancing is an efficient
form of exercise, amusement and
recreation for both sexes. It devel?
ops muscle coordination which re?
sults in grace of movement. Girls
run, roll hoops and skip the rope
during their more youthful years
but later their play becomes more
sedentary, and should be supple?
mented by class exercises and
games. Dancing is one of these.
Dancing is likewise a mind quicken
er. By fixing the attention, bringing
to bear the force of will on the com?
plicated actions of the body, it edu?
cates the mental faculties. This is
especially true of aesthetic dancing,
during the performance of which
the muscles of the arms and trunk
are used, as well as those of the
legs.
"Sometimes the dancing school is
misunderstood," continued the mas?
ter. "The dishonest and unscrupu?
lous dance hall proprietor may give
the clean dancing academy a bad
name, just as some classes of thea?
ters may give the theater a bad
name. The theater is a great insti?
tution, but it is all wrong from the
wrong standpoint. The same is true
of dancing and dancing schools. The
wrong angle may be applied to them
just as to the theater.
To Ask Church's Aid
The American National Associa?
tion during its coming convention in
New York will renew a long-studied
effort to gain the cooperation of the
Methodist Church in the promotion
of clean dancing. This denomina?
tion takes a stand in its "blue laws"
against dancing in any form, and
during the last General Conference,
some years ago, a resolution to
amend the "blue laws" was voted
down. A group of "progressive"
Methodists, led by J. Henry Smythe,
of New York, is to-day avowedly in
favor of dancing, and will carry the
fight into the next Methodist General
Conference. The "conservatives"
are said to be adamant in their re?
fusal to lift a ban prescribed almost
half a century ago on many forms of
amusement.
"Dancing is older than Christi?
anity," said the president of the
dancing masters. "It will live so
long as there is music. It is our
struggle to keep this form of amuse?
ment clean and moral, and we feel
that the Methodist Church can do
more for humanity by helping us
than by opposing dancing in general.
It is only the older and more con?
servative Methodists who now op?
pose dancing. Younger Methodists
favor it."
Allied with the dancing masters'
organization against what is termed
improper music and dancing, many
social and civic societies have
been doing their part. A pamphlet
issued by the organization, contain?
ing "Rules, Regulations and Sugges?
tions Governing S^pcial Dancing,"
j has been distributed by the thousand
^y social welfare societies and the
H-elfare department of the United
States government. Universities
and colleges, demanding authorita?
tive knowledge on proper and im?
proper dancing during school func?
tions, have beer, supplied with these
rules and regulations almost every
where in the United States.
The Actors' Eejuity Association,
?m organization composed of thou?
sands of actors and actresses, is an
able element allied against forms of
music and dancing which might tend
toward a bad effect on the general
public.
The dancing masters have success?
fully solicited the cooperation of
"^ong publishers, who have in turr?
i toned down suggestive titles and
Mthographs on sheet music. Phonr?
graph companies, spending tens o?
thousands of dollars monthly in
j brightly colored magazines, have
been prevailed upon to make their
advertising less "jazzy."
The General Federation of Worn
j en's Clubs, one of the most active
agencies in the United States, is
working for music reform. At the
biennial conference in June at D.es
Moines a resolution was passed con?
demning popular songs which smack
of vulgarity and initiating an open
campaign for better American music.
Mrs. Marx E. Oberndorf er (Anne
Shaw Faulkner), cf Chicago, wife
of the famous pianist, selected na
tional music chairman, is to-day
planning and directing the music
activities of more than 19,000 wom?
an's clubs. By means of music mem
ory contests in schools, churches, de?
partment stores, industries and in?
stitutions and the establishment of
i community music centers, she plans
to save a nation threatened by
"jazz" and "ragtime."
i The Federated Catholic Societies
of the United States'recently recog?
nized and indorsed the "anti-jazz'
movement, and through the federa?
tion magazine invited the attentior
of all Catholic schools and societie;
io the virtues of such a movement
Society's Aid I? Asked
In a quiet way appeals have gone
forth to society girls and women tc
i set the example in dancing for theii
less moneyed and perhaps less fortu
nate sister?the working giri?wh<
is prone to copy their methods.
"There are many rules to goven
?lancing, the American dancing maa
i ters explain in their pamphlet o
regulations. Here are some of them
"Dance music should be brigh
I and cheerful, properly accented am
the phrases well divided.
"Cheap, vulgar music of the ex
treme 'jazz' type invites cheap, vul
gar, meaningless dancing.
"It is needless to expect refinei
dancing when the music lacks all re
finement, for, after all, what is danc
ing but an interpretation of music?
There are ten plain "don'ts" fo
the proper dancing function.
"Don't permit 'jazz' music to b
j played. Such music almost force
dancers to use jerky half steps an
invites immoral variations.
"Don't permit young men to hoi
their partners tightly. Ofttimes thi
is the fault of the gentleman's part
ner. Both dancers should assume
light, graceful position.
"Don't permit partners to danc
with cheeks close or touching. Whe
dancers put their cheeks together
is simply a case of public love mai
ing.
The "N?eck Hold" Barred
"Don't permit meek holds.* TI
gentleman's arm should encircle h
partner's waist, his hand restin
lightly at her spine, just above tl
waistline, and the lady's left an
should not encircle the gentleman
shoulders or neck.
"So-called 'shimmy' dancing is
shaking or jerking of the upp<
body while taking short steps
standing still and should not 1
tolerated. Short ?idesteps, fir
PENTON T. BOTT, president of the American National
Association Masters of Dancing, which in its convention
here next week will begin a fight on jazz music and dancing.
The dancing positions shown are those approved by the Na?
tional Association.
I right, then left, when done continu?
ously, are not conducive to refined
dancing and should not be permitted.
"Don't permit elancers to take j
i either exceptionally long or short
steps. The proper dancing step
should be the same as a natural
walking one, except in exhibition
dancing, which belongs to the stage i
and not the ballroom.
"Don't dance from the waist up;
I dance from the waist down.
"Don't permit suggestive move
ments.
"Don't permit dancers to copy the
extremes that are now used on the
modern stage.
"For the benefit of refined people
don't hesitate to request objection?
able dancing couples to leave the
room. Remember that the majority
of the people want to dance cleanly."
"True refinement should be evi?
dent in every act of life," says the
book of regulations, "and this is
especially noticeable in a gentle
f
America Is Already
Turning Against
Vulgar Dances

man's attitude toward his partner
while dancing. Good t=ct* demands
that a gentleman stand a reasonable
distance from his partner, and that
he show due consideration in lead?
ing her through the different sleps.
Thoughtlessness on the part of both
lady and gentleman in taking out?
landish positions is responsible for
most of the criticism directed
:.gainst modern social dancing.
"All exaggerated movements, espe?
cially of the upper part of the body,
are in very bad taste in social danc?
ing and are never found with true
refinement and culture. Couples
dancing with their faces together
show such extreme* bad taste that
it should be unnecessary even to call
attention to it."
"All in all," says President Fenton
Botts, "the campaign has done much
to cleanse modern dancing, but
'jazz,' the root if it all, has done
more to eliminate itself than all the
campaigns.
"The American 'jazz' craze has
been like a popular celebration?for
a day or two all is enthusiasm, flags
and speeches. Soon it wanes and
dies its natural death."
Jazz, he believes, is now dying
that natural e'.eath, and European
nations which so quickly adopted the
American craze will see its Ameri?
can demise spread across the seas.
Jazz has had its day.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88076526/1922-01-25/ed-1/?sp=3&q=dance+dancing+jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ask the historian and he will tell' and serve it so mildly that all the
you that jazz is characteristic sign- te.ng may be lost. So remember that
board that indicates that the road ends it's all coated with frost—as com
soon and unless a turn to the right is pared with the real thing. It ."hall
taken the .nation or civilization travel. |be as gentle as expurgation, fumiga
ling along that road will soon be hurt- I tion and typewritten formaldehyde
ling over the precipice into oblivion, can make it. And yet, I warn you
Such the case with Babylon, Assyria, if you have a weak heart, if you faint
Egypt, Persia, Greece, Rome. In each easily, or if you feel when you see
case orgies of sensuous, lewd dancing a pretty blondined actress wearing
preceeded the downfall of these na- a peek-a-boo waist, stop at this line!
tions. Early in their history they Don't read farther at the peril of .your
were strong and clean of life. Then conscience and good health, because
came- the time when they were un- I mean to attempt to tell briefly the
clean, enervated by luxury, sapped by story of Pierre Louys, "Aphrodite
dissipation, and overcome by excess! Dr. Straton, the great New
-and weakened by licentiousness and York preacher speaking of the same
then in those latter days that were! spectacle says:
characterized by a prevelence of what "Nothing was left to the imagina
we would call today "jazz" they: tion. Every appeal was to the sen
danced themselves into the abyss. suos and the fleshly. .It was a night-
Let us ask the scienest what he mare of nude men and women, with
thinks -about this. bare legged negro men, in addition to,
"I do. not known about the loss .white men, squirming in and out and
of souls" says a biologist, "at least rubbing against the practically naked
in a- metaphyseal sense. What pen-1 white girls. It was an orgy of sen
alties may be incurred in the here- suality and shame, with men and wo
after by sinful or improper conduct men, in a condition of almost complete
on earth- are- beyond the ken of ex- undress, hugging each other, and slob.
bering over each other and rolling on
couches with each other, and danc
ing in feignod drunken revelry to
gether."
perimental science. But I do know
that natural law cannot be violated
with* impunity either for ourselves
or for the next generation. Hell
to mois a retrogression of the species.
In this sense I agree with any theo
logian as'• to the consequences of
degrading practices. There is no use
to quibble over details In so far
as jazz dancing relaxes morality and
undefatiines the institution of the fami
ly it is an- element of tremendous evil.
Besides the testimony of the scitfn
tist I woul 1 place the words of Prof.
J. Louis Guyon who characterizes
the "shimmey" as a "pelvic massage"
and who'' declares' that many couples
should' have marriage licences before
stepping upon the dance floor. Prof.
Guyon, by the way is the proprietor
of the largest dance hall on the west
side Of Chicago. It is significent that
he has barred jazz dancing and even
the "fox trot" He says:
"Ndw modern dancing is creating
an army of degenerates: It is break
ing down the moral resistance of the
younger generation and taking its
toll :in girls who succumb, under its
insidious influence, dancing the auto
mobile rides and "parties" that follow
the evenings dance. I am not a re
former, but I aiji against the "one
stepif andv any other vis-a-vis step.
Present conditions cannot go on. If
the publicdoes not become nauseated
with its ow.n ball-room conduct and
reform of its own accord, dancing
will have to be purified by statute:"
(from an interview in Chicago Tri- T'°r you HOLY and you are not doing
bune.) it.
The scientist is interested solely in "Peace, peace, there is no peace"
the physical and mental aspect but
he condemns because he knows that
70 per cent of the special surgical
operations upon women, are duedir-
ectl£ or indirectly to the disobedience
of these laws of God and Nature? He
alsff knows that 60 per cent of the
blintl are deprived the light of day
with. of lashed nerves that is behind
With the jazz dance and for it we
I -do*" not- believe a bridgroom or
biidc ever lived who did not register
AW. WHAT'S THE USE
HOPS ON CROWDED
0 TCOLLEN CAR-
^ome picture: That sew.. to be
the popular verdict on Rev. P. H.
Case's sermon Sunday n'ght relating
to drinking,. dancing and dissipation,
which constituted a large part of
the society doings of Babylon and
Borne, and more recently of Chicago
—and" Devils Lake. We are using
only a part of the sermon, and so we
leave the reader to the tender mercies
of the preacher:
"The other evening I called upon high and holy resolves when they, next generation but that perhaps
you to 'take stock' and presented heard "The Wedding March" Or our childrens children will come back
some of the facts to you. Let us Promise Me at their wedding. In the to sanity of life. He is right but for
face them this evening. What doj spiritual realm, too, music plays its one thing. That is the power of
they mean I am sure that anyone part and many a mar. has found his God. If we stop, think and then
that is fainninded will have to ad-j way to the Cross made clearer and (REPENT and turn to HIM he can
mit that the life today is tending easier by the sweet singing of God's and will cleanse us. There is a great
hellward, and our pace in that dir- Music. So many young souls tonight I revival needed today. It is needed
ection is swift. We are having a' are having seared upon the retina of among the poor and needy and among
"good time" as we go. All kinds their memories the picture of lost the outcasts of our cities and waste
of exhilaration and "joy rides" and virtue and stolen honor and the music places but I believe that even more
"jazz." We have jazz music, and jazz that accompanies that picture is this
pictures, and jazz married life. We demnable unspeakable jazz.
have turned on the gas, in fact have! Referring to jazz moving pictures,
clamped the accelerator down and as Mr. Case said the pictures he had seen
one man said in speaking of a recent here had been clean, with a few ex
"party" more truely than perhaps he ceptions. He quoted from Archie Bell
knew or meant: "We are having a dramatic critic of the Cleveland Sun
hell of a time" That is just it. I day-News Leader who said in review
er I do not ask you to take my! ing a certain play:
word for this. "{'11 put it in an ice shaker, cool it
/U/Y///A'
Why do I bring this in. Because
it is typical of the "jazz picture" of
today. They say it is art. It is the
Devil's art. Just the same art that
he used centuries ago in that "Grove
of Aphrodite" which is dep-cted in
that play and which ruin ad one cf thj
greatest civilizations the world has
ever known.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058393/1922-06-18/ed-1/?sp=34&q=dance+dances+dancing+jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Among those complaining have been the
French musicians who have been losing
employment because of the prevalence
of the darkey jazz bands. The banjo
and the saxophone have superseded the
violin and the flute, Only negroes are
considered to be the proper performers
on jazz instruments, and restaurants and
dance halls will employ only them. It
is called the "Black Peril."</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78001466/1921-09-19/ed-1/?sp=6&q=dancing+jazz+Jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Jazz dancing and jazz
music are, to repeat their own words
just exactly what one might expect
when the youth of land gads about
in sporty automobiles, simulates con
tempt for Mrs. Grundy's ideas and
shows a determination to do every
thing in a fast and snappy way.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045774/1921-03-13/ed-1/?sp=82&q=immoral+jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"Jazz, for example, I think, was invented
by imps for the torment of imbeciles. True,
it does not contain any distinct immoral
teaching, because music is not a didactic
art, but jazz does contain a real immoral
influence, because it confuses, bewilders, be
numbs and befuddles the mind through the
ears. It Is, in effect, the dope or knockout
drop In the art of sound,
"Laws against immoral art? Yes. I sup
pose every civilized community has found
It necessary to have something of that kind,
otherwise we should have cartloads of filth
dumped at our back doors every morning;
but these laws, it should be remembered, are
very imperfect in their scope and uncertain
in their application. They can do a little
to help I's, but not very much. To rely
upon legislation as a safeguard against
immorality in art?that is, as a real safe
guard?Is a great mistake.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038531/1919-09-03/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Immoral+Jazz</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>We appeal to mothers
and chaperones to help us elevate
dancing. We also appeal to musi
cians. They do not realize how much
help they can be. The way Is to cut
out so much "Jazz" and play the
muslo more like It Is written.
Six months ago we pre
dicted that the dancing teachers' as
sociation would wage war on "Jazz,"
and our prediictlon has come true.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045774/1922-10-15/ed-1/?sp=121&q=immoral+jazz&r=-0.023%2C0.044%2C0.699%2C0.353%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90066132/1922-03-16/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Immoral+Jazz&r=-0.036,1.158,0.341,0.172,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result><result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result><result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result><result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result><result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result> 
    </results>
  </topic>


  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>


  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
